what is e probably heard e is
approximately 2.718 and it is an
irrational number that will never repeat
but what is it I'll explain one way to
find it this writers the formula for
compounded interest let's set the
principal to a dollar set the interest
rate to 100 and set the time to one year
if we have one compounding per year it's
going to look like this this ends up
just being one plus one which is two now
if we did the same thing but with two
compoundings it would look like this
Which is higher than the two and then we
could do monthly compoundings that would
be n equals 12 and that would look
something like this which gives us
approximately 2.61304 so you can tell
we're getting closer and closer to that
value of e now if I keep going say do
daily compoundings that would look like
this right here and this number is
getting even closer to e if we did 10
000 compoundings this right here and we
could do 100 000 compoundings we're just
getting super close a million
compoundings gets us here and in the end
if we did it continuously that'd be like
n equal to Infinity the best way to
express that is with the limit as n
approaches infinity and that's going to
give us the number that is exactly e so
this right here is one definition of e I
hope this helps